Guide to the Rudolph Ruzicka Ephemera Collection, 1915-1956
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Rudolph Ruzicka Ephemera Collection
1915-1956
Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1883-1978
0.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Primarily printed material (greeting cards, pamphlets, programs) relating to or including Ruzicka's work
Biographical Note
Rudolph Ruzicka (1883–1978) was an artist known for his engraving, typeface design, illustrations and other work in the book world.
Scope and Content Note
Primarily printed material (greeting cards, pamphlets, programs) relating to or including Ruzicka's work. Of particular note is the work he did for Vassar College for the 50th anniversary of the opening of the college. Included are 11 of the 12 original drawings for the woodcuts used in Sketches of Vassar College.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Separated Materials
Some published materials were removed from this collection to be cataloged. For works illustrated by Rudolph Ruzicka, please consult the
Vassar College Online Catalog
.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Anniversaries, etc.
Subjects:
Artists--United States--20th century; Illustrators, American
Document Types:
Drawings (visual works)
VCL Categories
Art and Artists; Printing and Publishing; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, October 2009.
Acquisition Information
This is an artificial collection compiled by the Vassar College Library over a number of years.
Container List
- General
  - Biographical material (Folder 1.1)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 1.2)
  - Fanny Borden's bibliography (Folder 2.1)
  - Exhibition Catalog for traveling exhibit of Ruzicka's wood engravings, 1917 (Folder 2.2)
  - Exhibition invitation for "An Exhibition of Contemporary American Book Illustration" at the Lakeside Press Galleries, 1930 (Folder 2.3)
  - Prospectus for the Overbrook Press edition of Oscar Wilde's The Happy Prince..., 1936 (Folder 2.4)
  - New Year's greeting sheet for Ruth Greenough, 1940; (2 copies, 1 without text) (Folder 2.5)
  - Invitation to the American Institute of Graphic Arts party in honor of Ruzicka, May 1948 (Folder 2.6)
  - Promotional leaflet for the Grolier Club Ruzicka exhibit, 1948 (Folder 2.7)
  - Exhibit catalog for the Grolier Club exhibit, 1948; (2 copies) (Folder 2.8)
  - Programs from the inauguration of the President of M.I.T., 1949; (3 items) (Folder 2.9)
  - Meeting announcement for the Club of Odd Volumes, 1951 (Folder 2.10)
  - Book jacket for Willa Cather in Europe, 1956 (Folder 2.11)
  - Bookplate for H. Buxton Forman (Folder 2.12)
- Vassar College
  - 1916 calendar created for the 50th Anniversary, 1915; (in original box) (Box 1)
  - 1916 calendar created for the 50th Anniversary, 1915; (2 copies) (Folder 1.3)
  - General Program for 50th Anniversary, 1915 (Folder 1.4)
  - Invitations for the 50th Anniversary, 1915; (2 copies) (Folder 1.5)
  - Program of receptions for the 50th Anniversary, 1915; (2 copies) (Folder 1.6)
  - Founder's Day program, 1915; (2 copies) (Folder 1.7)
  - Library bookplates for Florence Donnell White (Folder 1.8)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Library (Folder 1.9)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Circle (Folder 1.10)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Observatory (Folder 1.11)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Main Building (Folder 1.12)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Sanders Laboratory (Folder 1.13)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The New England Building (Folder 1.14)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Students Building (Folder 1.15)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Museum (Folder 1.16)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — Sunset Hill and Bridge (Folder 1.17)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — The Chapel (Folder 1.18)
  - Drawings for the 50th Anniversary — Bird's-eye View from North Hall (Folder 1.19)
- Merrymount Press New Year's Greetings
  - 1913, (3 copies) (Folder 2.13)
  - 1916, (2 copies) (Folder 2.14)
  - 1917 (Folder 2.15)
  - 1918, (3 copies) (Folder 2.16)
  - 1919, (3 copies) (Folder 2.17)
  - 1920, (3 copies) (Folder 2.18)
  - 1921, (3 copies) (Folder 2.19)
  - 1922, (3 copies) (Folder 2.20)
  - 1923, (3 copies) (Folder 2.21)
  - 1924, (3 copies) (Folder 2.22)
  - 1925 (Folder 2.23)
  - 1926, (3 copies) (Folder 2.24)
  - 1927, (3 copies) (Folder 2.25)
  - 1928, (2 copies) (Folder 2.26)
  - 1929, (2 copies) (Folder 2.27)
  - 1930, (3 copies) (Folder 2.28)
  - 1931, (3 copies) (Folder 2.29)
  - 1932, (3 copies) (Folder 2.30)
  - 1933, (3 copies) (Folder 2.31)
  - 1934, (3 copies) (Folder 2.32)
  - 1935, (3 copies) (Folder 2.33)
  - 1936, (3 copies) (Folder 2.34)
  - 1937, (3 copies) (Folder 2.35)
  - 1938, (3 copies) (Folder 2.36)
  - 1939, (3 copies) (Folder 2.37)
  - 1940, (3 copies) (Folder 2.38)
  - 1941, (2 copies) (Folder 2.39)
  - 1942, (4 copies) (Folder 2.40)